[roars]
[narrator]
Strange beasts
and monsters.
[squeaking]
Vast riches.
Hidden treasures.
Evil haunts.
Uncharted frontiers.
The mysterious unknown.
The people who are captivated by the magic
in those words
are called...
Hunters.
[Hisoka Morow laughs]
I see, I see.
That settles it, then.
So you are the real one.
The Examiners are Hunters.
Each is hand-picked by the Exam committee
to do this job without pay.
Anyone who holds the title
we're vying for ourselves
could have deflected that attack.
And quite easily, I might add.
I shall take that as a compliment.
Thank you.
Still, should you choose
to attack me again for any reason,
I will have no choice but to report you
for attacking an Examiner
and have you immediately disqualified.
Is that clear?
Of course.
HISOKA X IS X SNEAKY
[narrator] The 368 applicants who made it
through the underground tunnel
find themselves in an unexplored land
teeming with strange creatures,
known as the Milsy Wetlands.
[Satotz] Now everyone,
please make sure to follow
close behind me.
[panting]
[cawing]
[Leorio grunts]
The fog is getting even thicker as we go.
Guys, here's our chance.
I say we take advantage of the fog
and get rid of him.
-Gon.
-Yeah?
-Let's try to move up to the front.
-Right.
The last thing we want to do is
lose sight of the Examiner right now.
I just want to put a little more distance
between Hisoka and us.
Staying too close is dangerous.
I can smell it.
Smell, huh?
[sniffs]
Huh?
I don't think he smells.
[loudly]
Hey, Leorio! Kurapika!
Killua says we should all move up
to the front of the pack.
Hey, calm down,
don't you feel the tension in the air?
[Leorio]
You idiot!
If I could reach the front
I'd already be there.
[Kurapika]
Go ahead, we'll meet you there.
Aww.
Come on, let's go.
Wait, hold on!
This is bad, with this fog
we can't tell which way we're going.
It's okay. As long as we don't lose sight
of the guys ahead of us.
Huh?
[cries out]
What in the hell is going on now?
Wow, what is that?
[man screams, grunts]
NOGGIN LUGGING TORTOISE
[all yelling]
[screaming]
[gasping]
[crying out]
MUSHROOM LAND MINE
[labored breathing]
[Leorio]
Huh? What's that?
Butterflies?
[gasping]
HYPNOSIS BUTTERFLY
Damn. Which way are we supposed to go?
Did we lose sight of him?
[Satotz] Now, everyone.
Please make sure
to follow close behind me.
He's over there.
[cheering]
[labored breathing]
[all crying out]
[gasps]
[Satotz] Now, everyone.
[caws]
Be sure to follow close behind me.
RUSE RAVEN
It can imitate human speech?
That sure was really close.
Yeah.
[grunting]
I wonder what's happening.
I can hear people screaming all around us.
That's why we need to be careful.
I haven't seen the guys in a while.
I just hope they're safe.
[both]
Huh?
[crying out]
FROG-IN-WAITING
[footsteps thudding loudly]
[loud squealing]
[Leorio yells]
Leorio!
[grunting]
[rumbling]
[roaring]
[grunts]
[Leorio]
Ow.
Leorio, now's our chance. Come on.
[loud thudding]
[creature snarls]
[grunts]
[groans]
[laughs] I guess he must not have liked
the way we tasted, huh?
It was this stuff.
[Gon Freeccs]
Oh, the drink Tonpa had.
I guess that's what saved us.
Yeah, probably so.
But I could have escaped without it.
I'm still pretty worried
about Leorio and Kurapika.
Forget about them.
We need to keep moving.
We can still make it
if we start right now.
It looks like we've lost sight
of the front runners.
[Leorio] Damn it.
Which way should we go?
Huh?
Hold on.
Look over there.
You're not Hunter material.
I've been thinking that
ever since we met last year.
We'll spare your life if you promise
you'll never take the Hunter Exam again.
-[Hisoka] Sure, why not.
-[gasping]
[Hisoka] I intend to pass,
so there's no need to retake it.
Oh yeah?
You idiot, just look at this fog.
Do you really think you can figure out
which way the main pack went in all this?
He's right.
We all failed this year.
No way we can catch up
with everyone else.
[laughs]
That's it, then?
You failed
so now you want to play Examiner?
Hunters require prey,
so why don't I play the Examiner?
All of you gentlemen claim to be
Hunter material.
But I'll be the judge.
[grunts]
You shut the hell up!
[all screaming]
[gasps]
[frightened moaning]
Now then...
[moaning]
Help! Help me.
Help...
[grunts]
Well?
[gasping]
[Hisoka]
How about you two?
Care to play Examiner?
HUNTER GLOSSARY
SATOTZ
[laughs]
All right!
We caught up with the main group, Gon.
Look.
That's weird.
He was right here a minute ago.
[groaning]
[Kurapika]
Okay, Leorio.
Wait for my signal,
then we run in opposite directions.
We what?
The fact of the matter is,
he's far more experienced
in actual combat situations.
The two of us won't stand a chance
against him.
We're short on time,
and we can't afford to waste more
on a fight we can't even win.
[cawing]
[loudly]
Now, run!
[footsteps growing fainter]
Hm.
I see.
A wise decision.
[laughs]
Hm?
[Leorio]
I just couldn't do it.
This may not be my fight,
but I can't sit back
and pretend nothing happened.
That's not my style.
See, the thing is...
[loudly] I can't run away.
Leorio!
[yelling loudly]
Hm.
I adore that look.
What?
[Hisoka grunts]
[Leorio]
Gon!
Did I make it?
[Hisoka sighs]
Not bad, little boy.
Is that a fishing pole?
How original.
I'd like to see it. Do you mind?
[Leorio]
Leave him alone.
[yells]
Your fight's with me!
[Gon cries out]
[grunts]
[Hisoka]
Did you come here to help your friend?
[gasps]
Such a good boy.
Hm. I adore that look.
[grunts]
Well done.
Very nice.
I'm beginning to get excited.
Right.
[Gon cries out]
[grunts]
[Gon gasping for air]
[laughs]
It's so delightful.
I love that look.
[Hisoka gasps]
[Gon grunts and coughs]
[Hisoka]
Don't worry.
I didn't kill your friend.
He's going to be just fine.
And that's because he passed.
[Hisoka laughs]
And yes, you pass as well.
Now go and become a good Hunter.
[beeping]
[man]
Hisoka. You should get back here.
We're almost reached the site
of the Second Phase.
Okay, be right there.
It's good to have friends, isn't it?
Can you find your own way back?
Good boy.
[Gon pants]
[Kurapika]
Gon, are you all right?
Ah, man.
Where is he?
I was sure Gon would be here.
[chattering]
[Gon]
This way.
-So you can really tell by the smell?
-Yeah.
Leorio's always wearing
this very unique kind of cologne.
I can smell him from
a few kilometers away, no problem.
[Kurapika]
Hm.
Hey, I've been thinking.
What do you think Hisoka was talking about
when he said that we both passed?
I'm not sure but I think
he might have been playing judge.
-Judge?
-Yes.
[Kurapika]
He must have his own benchmarks
for evaluating a person's power.
It's possible that he was measuring
the strength of each applicant.
Apparently you and Leorio
met his standards.
Whatever those happen to be.
Okay, right.
That makes sense. But I was powerless
to do anything to stop him.
You landed your first hit on him.
That's something, right?
That's only because I surprised him.
And besides,
Leorio didn't win his fight.
But Hisoka passed him anyway.
[Kurapika]
Hm, I wonder.
He could have sensed that the two of you
were sort of kindred spirits.
He sensed it?
It's possible that Hisoka could qualify
as a Hunter,
but I sincerely doubt it.
However,
I must admit that I'm impressed
by his superhuman agility
and the gracefulness of his technique.
Those who are blessed with unique talents
are often drawn to others
with unique gifts of their own.
It's likely that
based on his intuition and experience
Hisoka could tell that you both had
the skill and potential to become Hunters.
So from his perspective,
killing the two of you now
would have been a waste.
Oh no. Sorry.
That must sound horrible.
[Gon]
Mm-mm.
But I've got to say, it was actually
pretty exciting back there.
[Kurapika]
Huh?
[Gon] I was so scared that all I wanted
to do was run away.
But I couldn't.
because I was excited at the same time.
Isn't that weird?
[narrator] Gon had experienced mortal fear
for the first time.
And although the unfamiliar feelings
that accompany that fear
are quite confusing to him,
he cannot help but give in
to his growing curiosity.
At this stage, 220 candidates
have withdrawn from the Exam,
and 148 remain.
[Gon] Next time.
"A x Surprising x Challenge."
[Kurapika]
It's surprisingly challenging.
Wait. Gon, are you okay?
Subtitle translation
by Mitsuko Kitajima